cfl.ca 2019-12-30

# Privacy Policy - CFL.ca

**[** [EN](https://www.cfl.ca/privacy-policy/) | [FR](https://www.lcf.ca/politique-de-confidentialite/) | [DE](https://www.cfl.ca/datenschutzerklarung-fur-burger/)  **]**

_NOTICE OF POLICY CHANGE_

We have updated our Privacy Policy so please take note that several changes have been made to the terms below. Some of the key changes are summarized here:

  * **We have harmonized the privacy policies of the CFL and Member Clubs** so that all CFL fans can expect their Personal Information to be treated and protected in accordance with the same Privacy Policy. The CFL’s Privacy Policy now also applies to each CFL Member Club, who are hereafter referred to as “CFL Affiliates” for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.
  * **We have also updated the terms of the Privacy Policy**. Many of the terms from the previous iteration of the CFL and Member Clubs’ privacy policies have been clarified or modified. One important change in this joint Privacy Policy is that **Personal Information may, for limited and specified purposes, be shared and used by the CFL and Member Clubs**.
  * We have appended an updated Cookie Policy to explain what cookies are and how we use them.
  * **We have also amended the Privacy Policy in respect of citizens from European Union (“EU”) Member States.** The policy now reflects the requirements in respect of processing personal data of EU citizens as required by the General Data Protection Regulation ((EU) 2016/679) (“ **GDPR** “).

By using any of our Services, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information as described in our updated Privacy Policy. However, if you are an EU Citizen, your data will only be processed in accordance with one of the legal bases described in sections 4 and 10 of the Privacy Policy.  Please review our revised Privacy Policy below before continuing to enjoy our Services.

* * *

  1. _Headnote_

This privacy policy (the “ **Privacy Policy** ”) describes the manner in which the CFL and CFL Affiliates, including Member Clubs, may use and disclose Personal Information that is collected or received through our interactions with you and through  products, services, events and programs available at: cfl.ca, lfc.ca, CFL Pick ‘Em, TSN CFL Fantasy, Predict The Pick, CFLShop.ca, CFL Newsletters, CFL Forums, CFL Mobile App(s), GreyCupFestival.ca, bclions.com, esks.com, stampeders.com, riderville.com, ticats.ca, argonauts.ca, ottawaredblacks.com and montrealalouettes.com (collectively, our “ **Services** ”). In limited circumstances, **Personal Information collected or received by a Member Club may be shared and used by a Member Club or the CFL for a purpose expressly set out in this Privacy Policy** (see: “5. How the CFL and Member Clubs May Share and Use Personal Information”).

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, “ **CFL Affiliates** ” includes Member Clubs of the Canadian Football League (“ **Member Clubs** ”), as well as CFL Enterprises L.P., CFL Enterprises G.P. Inc., CFL Holdings G.P. Inc., and CFL Holdings L.P., (collectively, the “ **CFL** ,” “ **we** ,” “ **our** ,” “ **us** ”).

The CFL is the controller of all Personal Information, except where such Personal Information is collected by a Member Club via a Member Club website, in which case that Member Club will be the controller. Where you consent to a Member Club sharing your personal information to the CFL, the CFL will be the data controller.  The controller is responsible for all processing of your data.

By using any of our Services, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy. However, if you are an EU Citizen, your data will only be processed in accordance with one of the legal bases described in sections 4 and 10 of this Privacy Policy and listed in section 4.

  2. _Changes to the Privacy Policy_

Please note this Privacy Policy may be updated at times to reflect changes in our privacy practices. Any such changes will be posted on this page and where appropriate, notified to you when you start use of a Service for the first time following the change.  Changes will take effect immediately upon such posting or notification, and will apply to all collected information obtained by CFL after such posting or notification.  We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy periodically. The revised version is effective as of the published effective date. By your continued use of our Services, you acknowledge that any revised Privacy Policy will supersede any prior privacy policies to which you and your information may have been subject.

  3. _Personal Information We May Collect_

When you interact with us through our Services, we may collect data, including Personal Information from you or from other sources. “Personal Information” is information about an individual from which that person can be identified.

Data that we collect may be information that you directly provide to us, such as Personal Information you provide when you use our Services, or information that is passively or automatically collected from you, such as information collected from your browser or device.  Please consult our “Cookie Policy” for information about the type of cookies used on our websites and how that information is managed.

The data we collect primarily includes:

  * **Data that you provide directly when you register for, or use, the Services**. This data will vary, but typically consists of name, email address, postal address, phone number and other similar contact data.  We also receive data from the communications you send to us, such as customer service inquiries, product reviews and other feedback regarding the Services.
  * **User credentials** , such as username, password, password hints and similar security information used to create an account and authenticate users of the Services.
  * **Demographic data** , such as age, gender, country and language preference.
  * **Payment data** , such as credit card information and billing address.
  * **Device data** , such as type of device, operating system and other software installed on the device, device settings, IP address, device identifiers and error reports.
  * **Usage data** , such as the programs and features you access, items you purchase, and the timing, frequency and duration of your interactions through the Services.
  * **Location data** , such as IP addresses transmitted from your device.
  * **Information about your interests and preferences** , such as your favorite clubs and players, your home city or your communications preferences. In addition to what you provide directly, we may infer your interests and preferences from other data we collect, such as the content and advertisements you interact with while using the Services.
  * **Third party integrations**. If you connect your use of the Services through a third party service (e.g., a social media platform), the third party may share certain information from your third party account with us.
  * **Other third party data** , such as data from our affiliates, partners or vendors, data brokers or public sources. For example, if a third party runs a contest, they might share information about the people who entered the contest in accordance with their own privacy notices. We also might receive Personal Information from online ticket websites in accordance with their own privacy notices and/or through agreements with such online ticket websites, so we can see who has bought tickets to which game.

The CFL and Member Clubs have harmonized their Privacy Policies such that a Member Club or the CFL may collect Personal Information from a Member Club or the CFL for any of the limited purposes set out below (see: “5. How the CFL and Member Clubs May Share and Use Personal Information”).

  4. _How the CFL or a Member Club May Use Personal Information_

Please be advised that the CFL or a Member Club may use Personal Information for the following purposes. This section does _not_ permit the CFL or a Member Club to share or disclose Personal Information for any of the following purposes.

In respect of EU citizens, we will only use your Personal Information where we have a legal basis for doing so. The relevant legal bases that we rely on in respect of our processing of your Personal Information on our website, apps and in connection with the Services are described in section 10 of this Privacy Policy and are listed below in relation to each purpose.

**The CFL or a Member Club may use Personal Information** **to provide services**. We use the data we collect or receive to provide you with the Services you use or request. For example, we use this information to:

  * Create accounts;
  * Process transactions;
  * Provide technical support and respond to user inquiries;
  * Store Personal Information and keep records of our processing activities;
  * Comply with legal obligations that apply to us in connection with the provision of our websites, apps and Services;
  * Administer your participation in our events, contests, sweepstakes, games, or promotions;
  * Notify you about updates to our Services or send other communications that are relevant to your use of our Services; and
  * Protect you and us by enhancing our ability to detect and prevent fraud and potentially illegal activities in connection with our Services and otherwise enforce our rights.

If you are in an EU Member State, your Personal Information will be processed for this purpose under the lawful bases of:

  * Performance of a contract;
  * Legitimate interests; and/or
  * Compliance with a legal obligation.

**The CFL or a Member Club may use the data we collect and receive** **to improve our operation and Services.** We also use the data we collect or receive to provide content you may find relevant and interesting and to maintain and upgrade our operations and our Services. For example, we may use this information to:

  * Solicit, process, review and make use of input and feedback;
  * Identify and address technical issues on our Services; and
  * Customize your experiences based on location information or your online activities, including the content you view, the products you bid on or purchase, other Services of ours you use, and other information we collect or receive.

If you are in an EU Member State, your Personal Information will be processed for this purpose under the lawful basis of:

  * Legitimate interests.

**The CFL or a Member Club may use the data we collect and receive** **to provide effective advertising and marketing.** We also use the data we collect and receive to send you promotional communications. For example, we may use this information:

  * To send you electronic and other marketing messages about our Services, our venues, sponsors, our community and charitable endeavors, or other third-party business partners that may be tailored to your preferences and interests – for example, content related to your favorite club.
  * To conduct analytical and/or market research to enable us to improve the goods and services we offer.

If you are in an EU Member State, your Personal Information will be processed for this purpose under the lawful bases of:

  * Consent, where we send you direct marketing (except where we are marketing our own products and/or services which are similar to those in which you have previously purchased from us and several further conditions are met); and/or

Legitimate interests for all other marketing.  **The CFL or a Member Club may use the data we collect and receive** **to anonymize you.** We may take your Personal Information and anonymize it, after which we may use it for our analytics services (for instance, to find out the types of people who use certain Services), and to provide insights for ourselves and third parties.

If you are in an EU Member State, your Personal Information will be processed for this purpose under the lawful basis of:

  * Legitimate interests.

**The CFL or a Member Club may also use the data we collect and receive for other purposes** that will be described to you at the point of collection or for which you provide your consent.

  5. _How the CFL and Member Clubs May Share and Use Personal Information_

**The CFL and Member Clubs may share Personal Information** **among CFL Affiliates for the following purposes:**

  * **To conduct data analytics, consumer and/or market research** related to the goods and services we offer. This may involve merging Personal Information derived from multiple sources, including Member Clubs, for profile compilation purposes.
  * **To utilize data analytics, consumer and/or market research** for the purpose of improving Services.
  * **To send tailored communications and other marketing messages** to select recipients about Services and other offers.

  6. _How We May Disclose_ _Personal Information_ _to Third Parties_

We may share data we collect with select third parties for the purposes set out below.

**We may disclose the data we collect and receive** **to provide our** **Services.** We sometimes engage or partner with other companies to operate the Services or perform certain functions on our behalf – for example, maintaining our fan database, delivering messages and advertising, operating our websites and digital platforms. We may provide these companies with access to your Personal Information as needed for them to perform these functions in a manner consistent with this Policy. As at the date of this Privacy Policy, these companies are as follows: Mailchimp and Facebook.

**We may disclose the data we collect and receive** **when** **necessary under certain circumstances.** We may disclose your personal data to, for instance, law enforcement agencies and other public authorities, when we believe that disclosure is necessary to:

  * Comply with applicable law or respond to valid legal process.
  * Protect the safety and security of our fans or our Services.
  * Prevent fraud, abuse or other unlawful or unauthorized activities.
  * Protect the rights or property of us or third parties, including enforcing the terms of our agreements.

**We may also share your data for any other purpose as disclosed to you at the time of collection, or when we have obtained valid consent.** Please note that this Privacy Policy is not intended to limit our ability to share or disclose aggregated, pseudonymized or anonymized data in a manner that accords with applicable privacy law.

  7. _Security Safeguards for Personal Information_

We have adopted administrative and technical measures to help protect against loss, misuse, interference, disclosure, destruction, alteration and unauthorized access to the data you provide to us. We also maintain reasonable procedures to help ensure that such data is reliable for its intended use and is accurate, complete and current.

Please note that no data transmission or storage can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Despite our efforts to ensure that unauthorized third parties will not access or obtain your Personal Information through its Web site, complete confidentiality and security cannot currently be guaranteed on the Internet. The provision of services and communications via the Internet are subject to a risk of interception, loss, or alteration. As a result, while we strive to protect your information and privacy, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you disclose or transmit to the Services and cannot be responsible for the theft, destruction, or inadvertent disclosure of your information. By using our web services, you acknowledge and agree that we cannot be held responsible for damages resulting from the transmission of confidential information or Personal Information over the Internet and that such communications are at your own risk. **This does not affect any liability we might have under the GDPR in respect of the Personal Information of EU citizens.** In the event of a breach of security safeguards for Personal Information, the CFL, CFL Affiliates and business partners will comply with all reporting and notification obligations.

Please be advised that regardless of the geographic location from which you use our Services or provide Personal Information to us, your data may be transferred to, maintained in, and processed by the CFL, CFL Affiliates, service providers and our business partners in Canada and the United States. In respect of EU citizens, please see section 10 of this Privacy Policy for more information about how we safeguard international transfers of data.

We will retain Personal Information only for as long as reasonably necessary for the purposes set out above or for as long as required by law. In some circumstances we will anonymise your Personal Information (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes, in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

  8. _Your Access to Your Personal Information_

We will give you access to Personal Information we retain about you in accordance with the provisions of the _Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act_ or other applicable law (EU citizens should see section 10, below, which more fully describes their rights and California residents should see section 11 with respect to their rights). We will make every reasonable effort to keep your Personal Information accurate and up-to-date. Upon your request, you shall be informed of the existence, and where possible, of the use and disclosure of your Personal Information. You may verify the accuracy and completeness of your Personal Information, and may request that it be amended, if appropriate. Simply send us an e-mail at contact@cfl.ca and we will look after your request.

  9. _Privacy Policy for Children (Users Under 13 Years Old)_

Our services are not directed to, or intended for, children under 13 years of age.  We may use age screening mechanisms to help us determine if a user is under the age of 13.  However, if a parent or guardian of a child who is under 13 years of age discovers that Personal Information of such child has been submitted to CFL through the Services without the parent’s or guardian’s consent, CFL will use commercially reasonable measures to remove such Personal Information from CFL’s servers at the parent’s or guardian’s request.  To request the removal of such Personal Information, CFL, the parent or guardian must contact CFL as set forth in section 14, and provide all information requested by CFL to assist it in identifying the Personal Information to be removed.

  10. _European Privacy Rights_

This section of the Privacy Policy applies only if you use our Services covered by this Policy from a country that is a Member State of the European Union, (the “EU”), and supplements the provisions in this Privacy Policy.

Under the GDPR, you are entitled to additional rights, including: (i) the right to withdraw consent to processing where consent is the basis of processing; (ii) the right to access your Personal Information and certain other supplementary information; (iii) the right to object to certain types of processing, including processing based on Legitimate Interests or which is carried out for the purposes of direct marketing; (iv) the right to erasure of Personal Information about you, under certain conditions; (v) the right to demand that we restrict processing of your Personal Information, under certain conditions, if you believe we have exceeded the legitimate basis for processing, processing is no longer necessary, or believe your Personal Information is inaccurate; (vi) the right to data portability which means the ability to obtain and reuse your Personal Information for your own purposes across different services; (vii) the right object to decisions being taken by automated means which produce legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affect you, under certain conditions; (viii) the right to lodge a complaint with data protection authorities (<https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/board/members_en>); (viii) the right to be informed with clear, transparent and easily understandable information about how we use your Personal Information and your rights (this is why we are providing you with the information in this Privacy Policy); and (ix) the right to have your personal data corrected if it is inaccurate or incomplete. If you want to learn more about your rights under the _GDPR_ , you can visit the European Commission’s page on Data Protection at: <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/index_en.htm>.

In France, you are also entitled to provide us with your instructions as to the fate of your Personal Information after your death.

_Legal bases for processing_

The relevant legal bases for processing personal data for the purposes of GDPR are as follows:

**Consent:** means our processing of your personal data where you have signified your agreement by a statement or action for a specific purpose. Consent will only be valid if it is a freely given, specific, informed and unambiguous indication of what you want.

You can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us. This will not affect any processing that is carried out before you withdraw your consent.

**Legitimate interests:** means our processing of your personal data where this is necessary for our legitimate interests or those of a third party, except where these interests are overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. In this case, our legitimate interests are those that we have in:

  * operating our apps and websites;
  * providing the Services;
  * sending you electronic marketing communications in respect of the Services, including where these are similar to those in which you have previously requested from us;
  * detecting and preventing fraud and other criminal offences;
  * ensuring the quality of, and improving, the Services;
  * administering your account(s);
  * responding to your queries and requests;
  * communicating with you;
  * record keeping, statistical analysis, internal reporting and research purposes;
  * ensuring network and information security;
  * notifying you about changes to our services;
  * investigating any complaint you make;
  * providing evidence in any dispute or anticipated dispute between you and us;
  * analysing how our apps and website are being used;
  * customising various aspects of our apps and website to improve your experience;
  * understanding the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you;
  * business and disaster recovery (e.g. creating back-ups);
  * lawful document retention/storage purposes;
  * database management; and
  * protecting the rights, property, and/or safety of us, our personnel and others.

**Necessary for compliance with a legal obligation:** means our processing of your personal data where this is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation that applies to us.

**Necessary in connection with a contract:** means our processing of your personal data where this is necessary for the performance of a contract with you, or in order to take steps at your request before entering into a contract, for example to deliver the Services to you.

_International transfers_

The CFL, CFL Affiliates and Member Clubs are based outside of the European Economic Area (“ **EEA** “) and so their collection and processing of your personal data may involve a transfer of information outside the EEA.

When transferring your personal data outside the EEA, we ensure that security measures and appropriate safeguards are put in place to protect the personal data and to ensure that all transfers comply with applicable data protection law.

The CFL, CFL Affiliates and Members Clubs are based in Canada, which means that due to an adequacy decision by the European Commission, any Personal Information outlined in this Privacy Policy is covered by laws that provide an adequate level of protection.

Where we share your Personal Information with service providers or business partners based in the USA, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between Europe and the USA. For further details see <https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/international-dimension-data-protection/eu-us-data-transfers_en>.

  11. _California Residents’ Rights_

CFL will, to the extent required by any applicable law, disclose, delete or take any other action with respect to any Personal Information relating to you that is collected by CFL.  Specifically, if you are a resident of California and make such a request, CFL (and each third party to whom or which CFL transferred any Personal Information relating to you) will (a) disclose (i) the categories of any Personal Information relating to you that is collected by CFL, (ii) the categories of sources from whom or which such Personal Information is collected by CFL, (iii) the business or commercial purposes for CFL’s collecting such Personal Information, (iv) the categories of third parties to whom or which CFL transfers such Personal Information and (v) the specific pieces of such Personal Information collected by CFL, and (b) except in certain circumstances, delete such Personal Information.  Note, however, that laws that apply to one category of individuals do not confer the same benefits on other individuals not covered by such particular law.

  12. _Third Party Links_

Our Services may, from time to time, contain links to and from third parties.  Please note that these websites have their own privacy notices and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these notices or for any personal data that may be collected through these websites. Please check the privacy notices of these other websites before you submit any personal data to them.

  13. _If You Fail to Provide Personal Information_

Where we need to collect Personal Information by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you, and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with the Services). In this case, we may have to cancel the provision of the Service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

  14. _Contact Us_

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the privacy practices of the Services, please contact us by email at [contact@cfl.ca](mailto:contact@cfl.ca) or:

**Canadian Football League**  
50 Wellington Street East, 3rd Floor  
Toronto, Ontario M5E 1C8  
Attention: Privacy Policy  
Tel: (416) 322-9650  
Fax: (416) 322-9651
